# Nurudeen Saliu

Experienced software engineer with a passion for developing innovative programs that expedite the efficiency and effectiveness of organisational success. Well-versed in technology and writing code to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly.

24, Ibadan street, Ebute-metta west, Apapa Road, Lagos Nigeria.

+2347036509595

Email: saliu.nurudeen@yahoo.com Github:https://github.com/nurez305

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Decagon, Lagos — Software Engineer

MAY 2022 - DATE

- A member of a team that developed a Gift Card Solution for Babybliss project.
- Built projects with Nodejs, React.js and Javascript.
- Handled Database Management System with SQL like MySQL, Postgres, or NoSQL databases like MongoDB.
- Experience writing unit and integration test.

### **Telewest Technologies Ltd, Lagos** — *Accountant*

APRIL 2016 - JULY 2018

- Preparation of cashbook, debtor and creditor account, trial balance and income statement.
- Preparation of monthly budget and variance analysis.
- Preparation and communication of weekly and monthly reports to the management.
- Computation and payment of staff salaries on monthly basis.
- Attended to payment enquiries from staff members.
- Report to any letter on financial issue sent by the creditor

ACCESS BANK PLC, Lagos — Teller/Customer Service Officer

DECEMBER 2014 - MARCH 2016

- Work with applications like Pay arena, payDirect and eTranzact
- Handle dissatisfied customers in a polite and professional fashion.

#### **PROJECTS**

# Multi Page Website:

A complete responsive multi-page education/school website using HTML, CSS, and javascript.

Technologies Used - Html, Css and Javascript

Link: checkitoutnow.netlify.app

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- Tailwind
- Javascript
- Typescript
- React
- Redux
- React Hooks
- Nodejs
- Express Framework
- GraphQL
- MongoDB
- Postgresql
- Digital Ocean
- Heroku
- Firebase
- Jira
- Version Control with Git and Github.
- Test-Driven Development.

## Star War Site:

A single page application that fetches data from star war api

Technologies Used - Html, Css, Javascript and Star War Api.

**Link**: <a href="https://nurez-api.netlify.app">https://nurez-api.netlify.app</a>

## **Personal Portfolio Website:**

A portfolio website that should full details about me and my personal project

Technologies Used: Html, Css And Javascript

**Link**: <a href="https://nurezportfolio.netlify.app">https://nurezportfolio.netlify.app</a>

## **EDUCATION**

Kwara State Polytechnic - HND in Accounting

OCTOBER 2011 - JULY 2013

Upper Credit - Higher National Diploma in Accounting

From Kwara State Polytechnic